So, we're going to do now, we're going to graduate on to do more advanced event handlers.
So, let's take for instance the new restaurant.name that we have here.
For those that don't know, V model is a directive that lets you automatically update the value of the input and track it,
while also simultaneously tracking the input event and then updating set field.
So, to show that in execution here, what we're going to do actually, I'll just put it here,
restaurant or is it new restaurant new restaurant.name, new restaurant.name, okay?
So, here, when we go inside a restaurant, new, and I type, you'll notice that everything's updated as you want.
But, what if we only wanted to update, say, like, on when someone hits the space bar?
Let's just do something a little bit different.
Well, the way we would actually do this is we would need to hijack what's going on.
So, V model now no longer has worked because this is going to capture everything that we type on it.
So, what we're going to do now is we're going to break V model up into its two distinctive parts.
And that's what all people don't realize is that V model is really just syntactic sugar for what I'm about to show you.
So, first thing first is you're basically essentially binding the value of the element to this dynamic thing, new restaurant.name.
And then what it normally does with the V model is it also does an input event that will then basically say,
again, this is a little bit pseudo code, but event.target.value.
That's like at a high level what is essentially doing.
It's combining all that into one piece, making your life a lot easier because most of the time we're not trying to hijack the thing.
But let's say we want to hijack the thing and that we only wanted to update whenever we hit the space bar.
So, I'll use the update name function that we're going to call whenever this is being hit.
So, now if we go ahead and declare update name, it's a function and to show that it works, we're just going to log hello.
Alright, so over here, we'll see that when I go ahead and type, you see that hello is being triggered. That works as expected.
But we want to do something, we want to do a little bit more than that, we want to actually inspect what's going on.
If this is your first time working with custom events, what you need to know is that when you have this event here, it's automatically passed the event object as part of its default parameter.
So here what we can do is if I go ahead, I'm just going to type out event, oftentimes referred to as e, but I'm going to type event and let's log out the event this time.
We'll see now that when we go to new and type, you see that the input event is actually being called.
And this is great because what this means is we can now do something with said thing, right? It has the data, it has what not.
And okay, so this is pretty good, but you'll notice that actually the browser is giving us a hint already, but it's not just any event, it's an input event.
And so what we can do right is because right now if we try to do like event dot data, it's not really going to tell us anything because here's the thing about events is that, at least in the primary or in the form that it's in right now, there's no typing on it, right? It's any.
So you might be like, okay, I got this, I got this, I'm going to call it an event, yeah, I'm smart, and then you're going to realize, oh, this is pretty generic, it's just like, this is an event that takes place in the down.
That's that, it's essentially the any of events to be totally honest, like yes you're being descriptive that it's an event, but freely we could use a little bit more help.
And so what we do know is that it's an input event.
And when you get the input event, now the magic happens because all this stuff that you can do, I want to say, yep, all the properties that come with that object now suddenly appear in your auto complete.
So we can basically be like, okay, let's log the data for this, for example, or maybe let's see, do they have code, maybe code would be better.
Nope, not on this, oh, that's right, I know, I know why that's it, but it's fine.
So then here, so we'll log the data, so we come back in here now, let me clear the console is SDF space, okay, great.
So now what did I say, I said, I wanted to assign it when that happens, so what we can do is we can say, if data, if event dot data is equal to the space character, then what do we do?
We can say new restaurant dot name is actually a dot value dot name, see it'll get you.
Uh, that will be equivalent to event dot target, there you go.
So again, data itself is not auto completing for whatever reason, you're thinking like event dot target, like why is it, and I think basically the reason why we can't auto complete this, right, you're not seeing value anywhere is because
actually it doesn't know what event dot target is, for whatever reason.
And so what you can do instead, though, is you can basically tell that you can tell it's actually by wrapping your, your value in a parentheses and using type casting that it is an HTML element.
So your event target, you know, because again, you're the one coding this, you're like, I got this, it's not going to randomly get swapped out.
And from here, this is where the value property actually does not appear.
So now, if we save this and swap that over in yay, I'll wait, let me clear the console first space.
Now I've been yay, the full value actually does appear.
So here's the thing about this syntax, though, is that it takes a little getting used to, because this is not naturally how we would write it.
Honestly, I, most of us would expect to just do event dot target that value.
And while technically it'll work, so let's see, expected, let me force this real quick.
Okay, so I'm going to let TypeScript yell at me for now, this is fine.
TypeScript will yell, yeah.
So it does technically work.
And so this is where I, honestly, I think part of the issue sometimes comes in with when people start opting into TypeScript very, like, wholeheartedly.
Is that they get into this weird thing where they're like, wait, the thing that I'm used to doing now feels really awkward.
Like, what am I supposed to do? Like, I guess I can, if event dot target dot value exists, then log this.
But then it's like, okay, well, it's still saying that event dot target might be nulls.
Maybe I should get rid of that.
But then it's like, oh, well, event dot target could be any.
So you see that, like TypeScript is kind of going like, I don't know what it's supposed to be.
And so that's why typically then you would just, yeah, so we would just wrap this and then say as HTML input element, and now it's happy.
And so now we can take this whole thing and drop that here.
And now that we have that, we can go ahead new new name dot value, this is great.
So once again, we can test this by going, if we don't hit the space at all and just say, like, Ben website.
Create nothing's happened because it never got assigned.
I mean, just delete that now or actually going to actually wipe that out.
I do Ben space. You see that I got assigned up here.
Test.
Recommend.
Create.
Now it's actually assigned and created correctly.
So again, hijacking events can be a little bit tricky, but because you can type cast, if you, again, if you're telling type,
if you know what is going to be, it is nice because once again, it's easy to forget what you're putting things on.
So ultimately, it is basically a way for you to document what your intentions are, how it's supposed to work.
And then people can a lot more easily come into this update name in case it's bugging in the future and go, okay, this is what I'm kind of looking at without even looking at the template.
They can already do a lot of work from that.